HAYDEN ESTABROOK, PMP, B.A.Sc

LEAD DATA ANALYST. DATA STRATEGIST & MANAGEMENT CONSULTANT

Toronto, ON | Hayden. Estabrook@gmail.com | (647) 202-9528

OVERVIEW

Combining a dual background in advanced analytics and strategic consulting, I specialize in bridging the gap between technical and leadership teams, maximizing the potential of data and driving new creative and collaborative insights.

SQL | PowerBI | Python | Epic Cogito | SSMS | DAX | PowerQuery | NumPy | Pandas | Seaborn | scikit-learn | VBA | PowerPivot | Excel | MS Office

EXPERIENCE

ANALYTICS TEAM LEAD & LEAD DEVELOPER WOMEN'S COLLEGE HOSPITAL

MAY 2022 - PRESENT

Managing advanced analytic projects as the lead developer for Women's College Hospital. Working closely with leadership and clinical teams to design new tools, overcome strategic challenges, and identify novel applications of the hospital's data.

- Reduced referral non-compliance by 80% through working with clinical teams to standardize performance outcomes, develop targeted oversight tools, and implement real-time performance tracking.
- Developed a data-driven strategy for **responding to newly privatized surgeries** (Bill 60) and budgetary risks.
- Led cost and impact analysis to **strategize post-pandemic operation** of the hospital's COVID Acute Care Centre.
- Re-engineered reporting database architecture to achieve a 74% reduction in ETL runtime, facilitating a nightly transformation of 27M+ records.
- Empowered leadership across the hospital to leverage data for strategic decisions by designing a suite of targeted KPIs and dashboards to visually and intuitively address their most pressing needs in real-time.

DATA ANALYTICS & IMPLEMENTATION LEAD UNIVERSITY HEALTH NETWORK

APR. 2021 – MAY 2022

Supported the creation of Canada's first COVID-19 vaccination clinic by guiding critical decisions through real-time analytics. Led the development of KPIs, dashboards, and automation to inform operational trajectory in a rapidly-evolving landscape.

- Facilitated and prioritized the immunization of 150k+ at-risk Ontario residents against COVID-19.
- Developed a novel process to prioritize and automate rescheduling of 50k+ appointments resulting from changes to Ministry guidelines and vaccine availability.
- Achieved a 100% reduction in scheduling ineligible registrants by automating data transfers and implementing strict validation procedures.

SENIOR CONSULTANT ISAAC OPERATIONS

AUG. 2018 - MAR. 2021

Led and managed diverse consulting projects, leveraging operational data to develop strategy, align stakeholders, and achieve measurable improvement. Collaborated hands-on with clients to identify and implement solutions to meet their most pressing and complex strategic goals.

- Achieved a 50% reduction in caregiver COVID-19 exposure in GTA retirement homes by developing a novel crosscontamination analysis model and automating scheduling.
- Reduced annual operating costs by \$300k by creating new performance metrics and coaching coordination teams to schedule outpatient personal support care.
- Delivered a \$600k annual reduction in labor and material costs by leading a team to analyze FMCG manufacturing workflows, diagnose bottlenecks, and implement SOPs to increase productivity.

TRAINING & CERTIFICATION

Healthcare Analytics: AI, Big Data & Digital Transformation | Rotman School of Management

Project Management Professional (PMP) | Project Management Institute (PMI)

Python for Data Science and Machine Learning | Pierian training

PowerBI Advanced Training | Microsoft

Epic Analytic Systems Certification | Epic Healthcare (Cogito PM, Cogito Tools Admin, Cogito SQL, Clarity, Caboodle)

Management Skills for New Supervisors and Managers | Canadian Management Centre (CMC)

B.A.Sc Biochemical Engineering | Queen's University

President – Queen's Chemical Engineering Council | Team Captain – Queen's Experimental Sustainability Team | Varsity Academic All-Star | Andrew McMahon Standards of Excellence Award | Faculty of Engineering Dean's Scholar Distinction | DAAD RISE Germany Scholarship | NSERC Research Award | +8 Additional Awards

ACTIVITIES & Outside of work, I love to play the guitar, piano, and drums in my band – The Dirty Nelsons. I also love boxing, windsurfing, volleyball, board **INTERESTS** games, cooking, and photography!